<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ASSEMBLY_SET>
<ASSEMBLY accession="GCA_000151225.1" alias="ASM15122v1" center_name="WUGSC">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>GCA_000151225.1</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="WUGSC">ASM15122v1</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <TITLE>ASM15122v1 assembly for Methanobrevibacter smithii DSM 2374</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>&lt;P&gt;&lt;B&gt;&lt;I&gt;Methanobrevibacter smithii&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/B&gt;. &lt;I&gt;Methanobrevibacter smithii&lt;/I&gt; can be isolated from anoxic environments such as anaerobic digesters, anaerobic soil and sediment, and the gastrointestinal tracts of humans, ruminants and other animals. This organism is the dominant archaeal symbiont found in the human gut.&lt;P&gt;&lt;B&gt;&lt;I&gt;Methanobrevibacter smithii&lt;/I&gt; DSM 2374&lt;/B&gt;. &lt;I&gt;Methanobrevibacter smithii&lt;/I&gt; DSM 2374 was isolated from human feces and is part of a comprehensive, sequence-based survey of members of the normal human gut microbiota. The human gut microbiome sequencing project is a joint effort of the WU-GSC and the Center for Genome Sciences at Washington University School of Medicine, the purpose of this survey is to provide the general scientific community with a broad view of the gene content of 100 representatives of the major divisions represented in the intestine&apos;s microbial community. This information should provide a frame of reference for analyzing metagenomic studies of the human gut microbiome.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Comment&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Methanobrevibacter smithii F1 (GenBank Accession Number for 16S rDNA gene: U55235*) is a member of the domain Archea and has been isolated from human feces. The sequenced strain was obtained from Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen GmbH (DSMZ) (DSM 2374).~~* The available GenBank Accession Number is for the 16S rDNA gene of a strain related to Methanobrevibacter smithii F1, not this sequenced strain.~~We have performed one round of automated sequence improvement (pre-finishing), along with manual improvement that includes breaking apart any mis-assembly, and making manual joins where possible. Manual edits also are made where the consensus appears to be incorrect. All low quality data on the ends of contigs is removed. Contigs are ordered and oriented where possible.~~Coding sequences were predicted using GeneMark v3.3 and Glimmer2 v2.13. Intergenic regions not spanned by GeneMark and Glimmer2 were blasted against NCBI&apos;s non-redundant (NR) database and predictions generated based on protein alignments. tRNA genes were determined using tRNAscan-SE 1.23 and non-coding RNA genes by RNAmmer-1.2 and Rfam v8.0. Gene names are generated at the contig level and may not necessarily reflect any known order or orientation between contigs. ~~This work was supported by the National Human Genome Research Institute and the NIH Roadmap Human Microbiome Project [http://nihroadmap.nih.gov/hmp/].~~This is a reference genome for the Human Microbiome Project. This project is co-owned with the Human Microbiome Project DACC. ~Genome Coverage: 47x ~Sequencing Technology: 454~~Annotation was added to the contigs in February 2010~Product names were updated in June 2013&lt;/p&gt;</DESCRIPTION>
  <NAME>ASM15122v1</NAME>
  <ASSEMBLY_LEVEL>scaffold</ASSEMBLY_LEVEL>
  <GENOME_REPRESENTATION>full</GENOME_REPRESENTATION>
  <TAXON>
    <TAXON_ID>521002</TAXON_ID>
    <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Methanobrevibacter smithii DSM 2374</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    <STRAIN>DSM 2374</STRAIN>
  </TAXON>
  <SAMPLE_REF>
    <IDENTIFIERS>
      <PRIMARY_ID>SAMN00008834</PRIMARY_ID>
      <SECONDARY_ID>SRS010455</SECONDARY_ID>
    </IDENTIFIERS>
  </SAMPLE_REF>
  <STUDY_REF>
    <IDENTIFIERS>
      <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA29303</PRIMARY_ID>
    </IDENTIFIERS>
  </STUDY_REF>
  <WGS_SET>
    <PREFIX>ABYV</PREFIX>
    <VERSION>2</VERSION>
  </WGS_SET>
  <ASSEMBLY_LINKS>
    <ASSEMBLY_LINK>
      <URL_LINK>
        <LABEL>WGS_SET_FLATFILE</LABEL>
        <URL>ftp://ftp.ebi.ac.uk/pub/databases/ena/wgs/suppressed/aby/ABYV02.dat.gz</URL>
      </URL_LINK>
    </ASSEMBLY_LINK>
    <ASSEMBLY_LINK>
      <URL_LINK>
        <LABEL>WGS_SET_FASTA</LABEL>
        <URL>ftp://ftp.ebi.ac.uk/pub/databases/ena/wgs/suppressed/aby/ABYV02.fasta.gz</URL>
      </URL_LINK>
    </ASSEMBLY_LINK>
  </ASSEMBLY_LINKS>
  <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTES>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>total-length</TAG>
      <VALUE>1729275</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ungapped-length</TAG>
      <VALUE>1727775</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>n50</TAG>
      <VALUE>1719468</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>spanned-gaps</TAG>
      <VALUE>15</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>unspanned-gaps</TAG>
      <VALUE>0</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>scaffold-count</TAG>
      <VALUE>10</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>count-contig</TAG>
      <VALUE>25</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>contig-n50</TAG>
      <VALUE>1043555</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>contig-L50</TAG>
      <VALUE>1</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>contig-n75</TAG>
      <VALUE>175089</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>contig-n90</TAG>
      <VALUE>152994</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>scaf-L50</TAG>
      <VALUE>1</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>scaf-n75</TAG>
      <VALUE>1719468</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>scaf-n90</TAG>
      <VALUE>1719468</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>replicon-count</TAG>
      <VALUE>0</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>count-non-chromosome-replicon</TAG>
      <VALUE>0</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>count-alt-loci-units</TAG>
      <VALUE>0</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>count-regions</TAG>
      <VALUE>0</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>count-patches</TAG>
      <VALUE>0</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATED</TAG>
      <VALUE>2011-02-17</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
  </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTES>
</ASSEMBLY>
</ASSEMBLY_SET>
