<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ASSEMBLY_SET>
<ASSEMBLY accession="GCA_000151245.1" alias="ASM15124v1" center_name="Washington University Genome Sequencing Center">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>GCA_000151245.1</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Washington University Genome Sequencing Center">ASM15124v1</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <TITLE>ASM15124v1 assembly for Methanobrevibacter smithii DSM 2375</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>&lt;P&gt;&lt;B&gt;&lt;I&gt;Methanobrevibacter smithii&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/B&gt;. &lt;I&gt;Methanobrevibacter smithii&lt;/I&gt; can be isolated from anoxic environments such as anaerobic digesters, anaerobic soil and sediment, and the gastrointestinal tracts of humans, ruminants and other animals. This organism is the dominant archaeal symbiont found in the human gut.&lt;P&gt;&lt;B&gt;&lt;I&gt;Methanobrevibacter smithii&lt;/I&gt; DSM 2375&lt;/B&gt;. &lt;I&gt;Methanobrevibacter smithii&lt;/I&gt; DSM 2375 was isolated from human feces and is part of a comprehensive, sequence-based survey of members of the normal human gut microbiota. A joint effort of the WU-GSC and the Center for Genome Sciences at Washington University School of Medicine, the purpose of this survey is to provide the general scientific community with a broad view of the gene content of 100 representatives of the major divisions represented in the intestine&apos;s microbial community. This information should provide a frame of reference for analyzing metagenomic studies of the human gut microbiome.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Comment&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Methanobrevibacter smithii (GenBank Accession Number for 16S rDNA gene: U55234) is a member of the Euryarchaeota division of the domain Archea and has been isolated from human feces. The sequenced strain was obtained from Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen GmbH (DSMZ) (DSM 2375).~~This is a Newbler assembly (http://www.454.com/enabling-technology/the-software.asp) 1/2 plate of FLX PE 454 Data with a Q20 coverage of 49X.~~This sequenced strain is part of a comprehensive, sequence-based survey of members of the normal human gut microbiota. A joint effort of the WU-GSC and the Center for Genome Sciences at Washington University School of Medicine, the purpose of this survey is to provide the general scientific community with a broad view of the gene content of 100 representatives of the major divisions represented in the intestine&apos;s microbial community. This information should provide a frame of reference for analyzing metagenomic studies of the human gut microbiome. Further details of this effort are described in a white paper entitled &quot;Extending Our View of Self: the Human Gut Microbiome Initiative (HGMI)&quot; (http://www.genome.gov/Pages/Research/Sequencing/SeqProposals/HGMISeq.pdf). These studies are supported by National Human Genome Research Institute.~~Coding sequences were predicted using GeneMark v3.3 and Glimmer2 v2.13. Intergenic regions not spanned by GeneMark and Glimmer2 were blasted against NCBI&apos;s non-redundant (NR) database and predictions generated based on protein alignments. tRNA genes were determined using tRNAscan-SE 1.23 and non-coding RNA genes by RNAmmer-1.2 and Rfam v8.0. Gene names are generated at the contig level and may not necessarily reflect any known order or orientation between contigs. ~~For answers to your questions regarding this assembly or project, or any other GSC genome project, please visit our Genome Groups web page (http://genome.wustl.edu/genome_group_index.cgi) and email the designated contact person.~~Annotation was added to the contigs in February 2009.~~This is a reference genome for the Human Microbiome Project. This project is co-owned with the Human Microbiome Project DACC.&lt;/p&gt;</DESCRIPTION>
  <NAME>ASM15124v1</NAME>
  <ASSEMBLY_LEVEL>scaffold</ASSEMBLY_LEVEL>
  <GENOME_REPRESENTATION>full</GENOME_REPRESENTATION>
  <TAXON>
    <TAXON_ID>483214</TAXON_ID>
    <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Methanobrevibacter smithii DSM 2375</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    <STRAIN>DSM 2375</STRAIN>
  </TAXON>
  <SAMPLE_REF>
    <IDENTIFIERS>
      <PRIMARY_ID>SAMN00008835</PRIMARY_ID>
      <SECONDARY_ID>SRS010456</SECONDARY_ID>
    </IDENTIFIERS>
  </SAMPLE_REF>
  <STUDY_REF>
    <IDENTIFIERS>
      <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA27821</PRIMARY_ID>
    </IDENTIFIERS>
  </STUDY_REF>
  <WGS_SET>
    <PREFIX>ABYW</PREFIX>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
  </WGS_SET>
  <ASSEMBLY_LINKS>
    <ASSEMBLY_LINK>
      <URL_LINK>
        <LABEL>WGS_SET_FLATFILE</LABEL>
        <URL>ftp://ftp.ebi.ac.uk/pub/databases/ena/wgs/suppressed/aby/ABYW01.dat.gz</URL>
      </URL_LINK>
    </ASSEMBLY_LINK>
    <ASSEMBLY_LINK>
      <URL_LINK>
        <LABEL>WGS_SET_FASTA</LABEL>
        <URL>ftp://ftp.ebi.ac.uk/pub/databases/ena/wgs/suppressed/aby/ABYW01.fasta.gz</URL>
      </URL_LINK>
    </ASSEMBLY_LINK>
  </ASSEMBLY_LINKS>
  <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTES>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>total-length</TAG>
      <VALUE>1713248</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ungapped-length</TAG>
      <VALUE>1704865</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>n50</TAG>
      <VALUE>1524361</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>spanned-gaps</TAG>
      <VALUE>15</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>unspanned-gaps</TAG>
      <VALUE>0</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>scaffold-count</TAG>
      <VALUE>9</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>count-contig</TAG>
      <VALUE>24</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>contig-n50</TAG>
      <VALUE>226159</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>contig-L50</TAG>
      <VALUE>3</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>contig-n75</TAG>
      <VALUE>168984</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>contig-n90</TAG>
      <VALUE>65023</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>scaf-L50</TAG>
      <VALUE>1</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>scaf-n75</TAG>
      <VALUE>1524361</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>scaf-n90</TAG>
      <VALUE>179332</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>replicon-count</TAG>
      <VALUE>0</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>count-non-chromosome-replicon</TAG>
      <VALUE>0</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>count-alt-loci-units</TAG>
      <VALUE>0</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>count-regions</TAG>
      <VALUE>0</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>count-patches</TAG>
      <VALUE>0</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
    <ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATED</TAG>
      <VALUE>2018-05-21</VALUE>
    </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTE>
  </ASSEMBLY_ATTRIBUTES>
</ASSEMBLY>
</ASSEMBLY_SET>
